

Email: consultant@londonresearchinternational.com www.LondonResearchInternational.com

Mr S. Musharu

NATIONALITY: British & Zimbabwean

SUMMARY

I am a multi-skilled person with experience and qualifications in Business Management, Training, Training and Education, Engineering.

I have worked on projects for the Regional Economic Communities (RECs) of Africa - namely SADC, COMESA, ECOWSAS and EAC as a consultant doing the following: Capacity Building, Monitoring and Evaluation, Strategy Formulation, Strategic Plans, Risk Analyses, Writing Proposals, Training Needs Assessments, Change Management, Interviews to stakeholders, Restructuring and re-engineering of institutions, Designing of questionnaires for institutional audits, analysis of returned questionnaires, presentations, Auditing of Institutions and organisations and writing reports.

EDUCATION

2010: University of Bedfordshire- Post Graduate in Education (PGCE)

2006: University of Bedfordshire - Master of Business Administration (MBA)

1996: London Chamber of Commerce & Industry – Diploma in Marketing

1996: City & Guilds – Certificate in Quality Assurance

1995: Completion of Apprenticeship – Aircraft Avionics Engineer

1994: City & Guilds – Full Technological Certificate Electrical Engineering (FTC)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- 2013 / Tunisia: Worked on the African Legal Support Facility (ALSF) Work Plan and Operational Budget Report for 2013 - 2014 - ALSF
- 2013 /Zimbabwe: Worked on a Deutsche Gesellschaft für Internationale Zusammenarbeit (GIZ) facilitated project for Monitoring & Evaluation Practices in SADC, EAC & ECOWAS -SADC



Elizabeth House, First Floor, Block 2, 39 York Road, London, SE1 7NQ Tel: +44 (0)20 7378 7300 Fax: +44 (0)20 7183 1899

Email: consultant@londonresearchinternational.com

www.LondonResearchInternational.com

- 2011 2012/Zambia, Malawi, Egypt & Mauritius: Worked on a consultancy project for the restructuring of the Common Market for Eastern and Southern Africa (COMESA) secretariat.-COMESA/TMSA(Trade-Mark Southern Africa)
- 2012-2013/ Zimbabwe: Worked on an EU funded consultancy project for the International Border Management (IBM) for the SADC region. - Government of Zimbabwe/TMSA(Trade-Mark Southern Africa)
- 2012/Botswana: Worked on a consultancy project for formulating and devising the strategic plan for the Association of the SADC Chambers of Commerce & Industry (ASCCI).- ASCCI
- 2011/ Zimbabwe: Authored the proposal for ICT Strategy for Zimbabwe Ernst and Young Central Africa
- 2011 / Botswana: Worked on a Monitoring and Evaluation (M&E) consultancy project on Capacity Building of the ICT Sector of Botswana to diversify the economy of Botswana away from dependability on primary resources to using ICT services/products to drive the economy
 - Government of Botswana
- 2010-2011/England: Worked on a EU/LSIS funded project on "Embedding Sustainability" into the Engineering Curriculum at Bedford College – Bedford College
- 2008-2011/England :Curriculum Design , Assessment & Delivery of Vocational Courses to Students – Bedford College
- 2003-2008/England: Technical Support manager in charge of Engineering Equipment, Training, Quality issues and New Product Development – Coca-Cola Enterprises

Sectors:

- Agriculture, Fishing and Forestry
- Law and Justice and Public Administration
- Information and Communications
- Education
- Finance
- Health and Other Social Services
- **Industry and Trade**
- **Energy and Mining**
- Transportation
- Water, Sanitation and Flood Protection
- Science and Technology



Elizabeth House, First Floor, Block 2, 39 York Road, London, SE1 7NQ Tel: +44 (0)20 7378 7300 Fax: +44 (0)20 7183 1899

Email: consultant@londonresearchinternational.com www.LondonResearchInternational.com

Areas of Expertise:

- Civil Engineering
- Mechanical Engineering
- Electrical Engineering
- Economic and Financial Feasibility
- Environmental Impact Assessment
- Transportation/Infrastructure Planning
- Community Planning
- Water/Sewer
- Energy
- IT/Communication
- Agriculture
- Capacity Development (manpower and institutions)
- Marketing
- Project Management
- Accounting
- Legal
- Procurement
- Management
- Other: Vocational Education, Monitoring & Evaluation (M&E)

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

Member of Chartered Management Institution (MCMI)

Member of Institute of Engineering & Technology (MIET)

LANGUAGES

English, Shona, Ndebele, Zulu, Nyanja and basic French